<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Even - A super concise theme for Hugo</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Even - A super concise theme for Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Minimalistic Approach to Zsh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/zsh_installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/zsh_installation/</guid>
      <description>Although I&#39;m on Debian Linux, Apple&#39;s recent announcement about replacing Bash with Zsh on MacOS made me take a look at Z-shell aka zsh. It&#39;s a POSIX compliant Bash alternative that has been around for quite a long time. While Bash shell&#39;s efficiency and ubiquity make it hard to think about changing the default shell of your primary development machine, I find its features as an interactive shell to be somewhat limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dipping Toes into Bash Scripting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/brisk_bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/brisk_bash/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Okay, here&#39;s a confession. I&#39;m the type of person who never picks up a new skill unless I absolutely have to. Although I have been using Debian based Linux personally and professionally for over a year, my knowledge on the command line and bash scripting have hopelessly remained stuck in a local minimum. Sure, I know my way around the terminal but working as a data scientist didn&#39;t require me to know the nitty-gritty details of bash scripting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brisk Guide to Set Up MySQL on Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/mysql_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/mysql_linux/</guid>
      <description>Setting Up Installation This part describes a basic installation of a MySQL 5.7 database server on Ubuntu Linux, 18.04 to be specific.
sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install mysql-server  Allow Remote Access If you want to connect to the MySQL database from another machine, you must open a port in your server’s firewall (the default port is 3306). This is not necessary if you intend to run the application that uses MySQL on the same server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brisk Guide to Install Tensorflow GPU on Linux (Ubuntu 18.04/18.10)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/tensorflow1.12_install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/tensorflow1.12_install/</guid>
      <description>My system configuration  AMD Ryzen 2600 16 GB DDR4 3200 MHz memory GTX 1050 ti 4 GB Ubuntu 18.04 Bionic Beaver  Remove Nvidia Nouveau Driver Blacklist the driver $ sudo bash -c &amp;quot;echo blacklist nouveau &amp;gt; /etc/modprobe.d/blacklist-nvidia-nouveau.conf&amp;quot; $ sudo bash -c &amp;quot;echo options nouveau modeset=0 &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/modprobe.d/blacklist-nvidia-nouveau.conf&amp;quot; Confirm the content of the new modprobe config file $ cat /etc/modprobe.d/blacklist-nvidia-nouveau.conf blacklist nouveau options nouveau modeset=0 Update kernel initramfs $ sudo update-initramfs -u Reboot $ sudo reboot Remove Any Other NVIDIA Driver Add the graphics driver PPA $ sudo add-apt-repository ppa:graphics-drivers/ppa $ sudo apt-get update Purge the driver $ sudo apt-get purge nvidia* Reboot $ sudo reboot Install Proprietary Nvidia Driver $ sudo apt update $ sudo ubuntu-drivers autoinstall $ sudo reboot After this, nvidia-smi command will output the GPU status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electric Nostalgia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/electric_nostalgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/electric_nostalgia/</guid>
      <description>There are days when writer’s block rusts my fingers as they squeak like a battered door while I struggle on a mechanical keyboard and then, there are these moments that kick in a chain reaction of nostalgic thoughts, electrifying the neurons at a supersonic pace. As the dusk was nearing, I was sifting through the pages of ‘Fooled by Randomness’ by Nassim Nicholas Taleb when the call for evening prayer disintegrated the solemn silence before Iftar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Murder Of Roger Ackroyd</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/murder_ackroyd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/murder_ackroyd/</guid>
      <description>For me, so far, 2017 has been a year of picking up books sequentially and never actually finishing them completely either because I’m trying to bring up some conscious changes to the genre of books that I normally read or the books I’m recently picking up are actually shallow compared to the ones I would spontaneously enjoy. Defeated, I was meaning to snatch up something from the cornucopia of my beloved author, Agatha Christie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>